<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Alejandro R. Urzúa</title>
        <link>https://arurz.xyz/</link>
        <description>Personal webpage</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://arurz.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>[NEW PREPRINT] Unitary rotation of pixellated polychromatic images</title>
    <link>https://arurz.xyz/preprint_polychromatic/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arurz.xyz/preprint_polychromatic/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/notices/images/poly.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Figure: The well-known Lena with $N = 52$ pixels, rotated consecutively by $\theta = \pi/4$. 
We address the task to unitarily rotate stacked two-dimensional real matrices of dimension $N$ that resemble color channels of polychromatic pixellated images. Carefully understanding of digital artifacts arising from the discrete and finite nature of the transformation is done. We developed an understanding of the so-called Gibbs-like phenomena in finite two-dimensional signals.

  -- Preprint PDF at arXiv $\rightarrow$ https://arxiv.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Gibbs-like oscillations in one-dimensional discrete signals</title>
    <link>https://arurz.xyz/gibbs-phenomena-in-signals/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arurz.xyz/gibbs-phenomena-in-signals/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1 Introduction: Continuous signals It is well known that a well suitable periodic one-dimensional signal (or function) $f(x)$ in $\mathcal{L}^{2}$ can be expanded and encoded in the coefficients of the Fourier series $f_{n}$ [1, pp.]
$$f_{n} = \left(2\pi\right)^{-1/2}\int_{-\pi}^{\pi}dx f(x)\exp\left(-\mathrm{i}nx\right),\qquad (1)$$
that are used to reconstruct the original waveform $f(x)$ up to a $N$ degree,
$$f(x) \equiv \left(2\pi\right)^{-1/2}\sum\limits_{n = 0}^{N - 1}f_{n}\exp\left(\mathrm{i}nx\right).\qquad (2)$$
The Gibbs phenomena is assigned to the behavior of the reconstructed signal under a truncation of the sum on $(2)$, at most $K &lt; N$.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamical invariant for the position-positon coupled harmonic oscillators</title>
    <link>https://arurz.xyz/f2invariant/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://arurz.xyz/f2invariant/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Introduction Recently I found a new very nice article about dynamical invariants by Kumar et al. [1], that is based on findings by Struckmeier and Riedel [2]. I been involved in the solution of time-dependent systems by means of orthogonal and Lewis-Ermakov invariants [3, 4] and I want to expand the understanding of this mathematical devices on systems who behave like damping phenomena. The methods they provide are interesting because of the generalization over the standard invariants.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
