<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Alejandro R. Urzúa</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Alejandro R. Urzúa</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>[NEW PUBLISHED RESEARCH]  Unitary rotation of pixellated polychromatic images </title>
    <link>/poly_article/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/poly_article/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ We, AR. Urzúa and KB. Wolf recently published a research on Unitary rotation of pixellated polychromatic images on Journal of the Optical Society of America A.
Urzua, A., &amp; Wolf, K. B. (2022). Unitary rotation of pixellated polychromatic images. In Journal of the Optical Society of America A. Optica Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1364/josaa.462530 ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>[NEW PUBLISHED RESEARCH] Intrinsic decoherence for the displaced harmonic oscillator</title>
    <link>/disp_article/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/disp_article/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ We, AR. Urzúa and HM Moya-Cessa recently published a research on Intrinsic decoherence in the displaced quantum harmonic oscillator on Pramana Journal of Physics.
Urzúa, A. R., &amp; Moya-Cessa, H. M. (2022). Intrinsic decoherence for the displaced harmonic oscillator. In Pramana (Vol. 96, Issue 2). Springer Science and Business Media LLC. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12043-022-02319-w ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Computation Methods on Quantum systems: Special Issue Submission Proposal</title>
    <link>/mdpisi/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/mdpisi/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/notices/images/banner.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>We invite to submit proposal for the new Special Issue on MDPI&rsquo;s Axioms Journal.
The scope of the issue is to collect works around the mathematical, logical, and analytical methods of quantum systems. We encourage related research on true quantum systems, and hybrids. The topics of which we expect works are regarded, but not limited to,
Solutions on dynamical equations Time-dependent and independent systems Operational approaches to quantum, classical, and hybrid systems Algebraic structures Group theoretical methods Numerical and computational analysis We encourage to send proposals to the Guest Editors or directly on the website of the special issue: http://mdpi.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Three-dimensional position-to-modes discrete mapping</title>
    <link>/pos2mod/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/pos2mod/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction On previous works [1, 2], we explore the map between position and mode basis for discrete two-dimensional fields, aka., pixellated images. The extension to the three-dimensional case is straightforward since the discrete and finite basis spawned by the Kravchuk functions $\psi_{n}^{(j)}(q)$ is complete and their composition to upper dimensions is the direct product of the individual basis,
$$\begin{aligned}\Psi_{n_{1}, n_{2}, n_{3}}^{(j)}(q_{1}, q_{2}, q_{3}) &amp;= \psi_{n_{1}}^{(j)}(q_{1})\otimes\psi_{n_{2}}^{(j)}(q_{2})\otimes \psi_{n_{3}}^{(j)}(q_{3})\\ &amp;=: \langle q_{1}, q_{2}, q_{3}\vert n_{1}, n_{2}, n_{3}\rangle.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Gibbs-like oscillations in one-dimensional discrete signals</title>
    <link>/gibbs-phenomena-in-signals/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/gibbs-phenomena-in-signals/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1 Introduction: Continuous signals It is well known that a well suitable periodic one-dimensional signal (or function) $f(x)$ in $\mathcal{L}^{2}$ can be expanded and encoded in the coefficients of the Fourier series $f_{n}$ [1, pp.]
$$f_{n} = \left(2\pi\right)^{-1/2}\int_{-\pi}^{\pi}dx f(x)\exp\left(-\mathrm{i}nx\right),\qquad (1)$$
that are used to reconstruct the original waveform $f(x)$ up to a $N$ degree,
$$f(x) \equiv \left(2\pi\right)^{-1/2}\sum\limits_{n = 0}^{N - 1}f_{n}\exp\left(\mathrm{i}nx\right).\qquad (2)$$
The Gibbs phenomena is assigned to the behavior of the reconstructed signal under a truncation of the sum on $(2)$, at most $K &lt; N$.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamical invariant for the position-positon coupled harmonic oscillators</title>
    <link>/f2invariant/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/f2invariant/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Introduction Recently I found a new very nice article about dynamical invariants by Kumar et al. [1], that is based on findings by Struckmeier and Riedel [2]. I been involved in the solution of time-dependent systems by means of orthogonal and Lewis-Ermakov invariants [3, 4] and I want to expand the understanding of this mathematical devices on systems who behave like damping phenomena. The methods they provide are interesting because of the generalization over the standard invariants.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
